<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Weyway - Raids and Dungeons]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>Weyway - Raids and Dungeons</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 08:12:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 08:12:21 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[W'eylyn Mavourneen]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>W&apos;eylyn Mavourneen</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[ Home]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Weyway's Raid and Dungeons pages live here.
This is meant to be a quicker way to browse between text-based guides from our FC discord.<br>
Use the sidebar to browse between each guide.
<br><img alt="xd.png" src="images\xd.png"><br><br>Latest Changes<br>]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[W'eylyn Mavourneen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 08:07:27 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="images\xd.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images\xd.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aloalo Island]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="Aloalo_Island1-1.jpg" src="images\aloalo_island1-1.jpg"><br>
In a seldom-traveled corner of the south sea isles lies Aloalo, an island filled with lush vegetation and teeming with vibrant wildlife. Yet the survival of this paradise hinges on a delicate natural balance which has only grown more precarious since the island's stewards departed a century ago. Answering the plea of a messenger most peculiar, you must join Matsya on a journey to restore order to Aloalo, and in the process uncover secrets long forgotten
- In-game description
<br><br><br>Aloalo Island is a level 90 Variant Dungeon introduced in patch 6.51 with Endwalker.<br><br>Important
To unlock this Variant Dungeon you must complete the associated quests starting on <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://ffxiv.consolegameswiki.com/wiki/Stranger_from_Paradise" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://ffxiv.consolegameswiki.com/wiki/Stranger_from_Paradise" target="_blank">Stranger from Paradise</a>
<br><br><br>Each conservation record is gained by completing one of the twelve endings.<br>
These are split by three paths that you must choose at the start.<br><br><br>
<br>When prompted by Matsya about fishing (he’ll have an exclamation point above his head), tell him: “We should press on.”
<br>Ignore Zeal-blind Zozone, letting his HP deplete. He’ll call you a bastard and run off when his health bar empties.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>When prompted by Matsya about fishing (he’ll have an exclamation point above his head), tell him: “We should press on.”
<br>Help Zeal-blind Zozone.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>When prompted by Mastya about fishing (he’ll have an exclamation point above his head), tell him: “Fish to your heart’s content.”
<br>Interact with the patch of sand on the right and give the bait to Matsya.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>When prompted by Mastya about fishing (he’ll have an exclamation point above his head), tell him: “Fish to your heart’s content.”
<br>Interact with the mound of rocks on the left and give the bait to Matsya.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br><br>
<br>After the midboss, kill the crawlers and treant in any order as long as they’re not standing on the sigil on the floor.
<br>Kill the next sets of monsters normally and proceed to the boss.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>After the midboss, kill the crawlers and treant in any order as long as they’re not standing on the sigil on the floor.
<br>On the next set of monsters, run through the red flower bushes and follow the path to scare off the armadillo-like rodents.
<br>On the next set of monsters (again), do the same thing as above — run through the red flowers to find the armadillo-like rodents and scare them off.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>After the midboss, pull the crawlers and treant to be on top of the sigil on the floor. While staying on the sigil, kill the treant first, and then kill the crawlers.
<br>Head up the new path and kill the set of monsters.
<br>On the next and final set of monsters, fight the monsters, but do not hit Jolly-tailed J’jhimei.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>After the midboss, pull the crawlers and treant to be on top of the sigil on the floor. While staying on the sigil, kill the treant first, and then kill the crawlers.
<br>Head up the new path and kill the set of monsters.
<br>On the next and final set of monsters, attack Jolly-tailed J’jhimei.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br><br>
<br>When you approach Statice the pixie, select: "Well go on, don't keep them to yourself."
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>When you approach Statice the pixie, select: “I’m not interested in your ‘secrets.”
<br>When prompted again, select: “I don’t know if I can...”
<br>When prompted for the third time, select: “You just have a...wicked air about you.”
<br>Don’t interact with any of the treasures you see after taking the new path.
<br>Pull the lever to take the path down.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>When you approach Statice the pixie, select: “I’m not interested in your ‘secrets.”
<br>When prompted again, select: “I don’t know if I can...”
<br>When prompted for the third time, select: “You just have a...wicked air about you.
<br>Interact with the treasure to reveal the mimics and kill them.
<br>Pull the lever to take the path down.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>When you approach Statice the pixie, select: “I’m not interested in your ‘secrets.”
<br>When prompted again, select: “I don’t know if I can...”
<br>When prompted for the third time, select: “You just have a...wicked air about you.”
<br>Don’t interact with any of the treasures you see after taking the new path.
<br>Do not pull the lever in the room with the statues.
<br>In the statue room, complete the rituals for each statue.
<br>Continue the steps bellow after the rituals.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>You may copy the messages marked as Say and paste them as normal chat in-game.<br><br>Say in chat
O messenger from beyond the horizon, hear me.
<br>Move
Two clockwise laps around all the statues.<br>
Then one counterclockwise lap.
<br>Emote
In front of Whale do /dance emote.
<br><br>Say in chat
O wayfarer of land and sea, hear me.
<br>Move
Two counterclockwise laps around all the statues.
<br>Emote
In front of Turtle do /bow emote.
<br><br>Say in chat
O dancer of the skies, hear me.
<br>Emote
In front of Sparrow do /blowkiss emote.
<br>Move
One clockwise lap around all the statues.
<br>Emote
In front of Sparrow do /dance emote.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>After doing all three rituals, a new path will open up. Head down.
<br>Take out the monsters and Wobble-kneed Whasbyrm.
<br>Interact with the sack that he drops.
<br>Place the statues obtained from the sack on the pedestals. 
<br>Sparrow on the first pedestal.
<br>Whale on the second pedestal.
<br>Turtle on the third pedestal.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br>Completing all the paths unlocks the Spectral Statice Whistle.<br><img alt="Aloalo_Island3.jpg" src="images\aloalo_island3.jpg"><br><br><br><br><br><br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br>Date: 28/04/2024
Collected by: W'eylyn Mavourneen
Copy]]></description><link>aloalo-island.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Aloalo Island.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[W'eylyn Mavourneen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 07:46:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="images\aloalo_island1-1.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images\aloalo_island1-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mount Rokkon]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="Mount_Rokkon1.jpg" src="images\mount_rokkon1.jpg"><br>
On Hingashi's westernmost isle of Shishu lies the long-venerated Mount Rokkon. Once refuge for humble monks and weary pilgrims, the holy site lately fell to a host of malevolent mononoke, spurring the local liege lord to take the unprecedented step of inviting ijin to assist in reclaiming its slopes. As in his wont, Hancock has secured the promise of valuable rewards in exchange for his—and your—assistance, but each of these treasures has a life of its own...
- In-game description
<br><br><br>Mount Rokkon is a level 90 Variant Dungeon introduced in patch 6.45 with Endwalker.<br><br>Important
To unlock this Variant Dungeon you must complete the associated quests starting on <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://ffxiv.consolegameswiki.com/wiki/Mononoke_Aware" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://ffxiv.consolegameswiki.com/wiki/Mononoke_Aware" target="_blank">Mononoke Aware</a>
<br><br><br>Each exorcism is gained by completing one of the twelve endings.<br>
These are split by three paths that you must choose.<br><br><br>
<br>Ignore the statues and interact with the orb in the auspice room.
<br>Interact with the katana box in the following room.
<br>Boss Tip!
Moko the Restless will gain Untempered Sword which makes AoEs from the edge of the arena.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>Ignore the statues and interact with the orb in the auspice room.
<br>Ignore with the katana box in the following room.
<br>Boss Tip!
Moko the Restless will gain Moonless Night, a set of half-room circle AoEs.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br><img alt="statues.jpg" src="images\statues.jpg"><br>
<br>Face the Suzaku statue south and the Seiryu statue east. Rotate them by interacting.
<br>Interact with the orb after.
<br>ALLOW the Shishu Apa to complete its Water III cast to extinguish the lanterns.
<br>Boss Tip!
Moko the Restless will gain Tengu-Yobi, line knock-backs from the edge of the arena.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>Face the Suzaku statue south and the Seiryu statue east. Rotate them by interacting.
<br>Interact with the orb after.
<br>STOP the Shishu Apa from completing it's Water III cast by interrupting it.
<br>Boss Tip!
Moko the Restless will gain Spirit Spark. AoEs on the arena accompanied with heads that float towards players and do damage on contact.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br><br>
<br>Continue the path until the pile of crates.
<br>Ignore the crates and go right.
<br>Reach the Shishu White Baboon and spare it by choosing the first option:

<br>"Very well - we have a deal."


<br>Boss Tip!
The baboon will spawn during the Gorai the Uncaged fight, chain players to it, and start casting Self-Destruct. Kill the baboon before the cast finishes.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>Continue the path until the pile of crates.
<br>Ignore the crates and go right.
<br>Reach the Shishu White Baboon and defeat it  by choosing the second option:

<br>"Give me a moment to think..."


<br>Boss Tip!
Gorai the Uncaged will summon thunder orbs with Thundercall, spawn AoEs with Humble Hammer, and combine the two abilities.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br><img alt="crates.jpg" src="images\crates.jpg"><br>
<br>Continue the path until the pile of crates.
<br>Climb the pile of crates to the second floor.
<br>Pull the Woven Rope.
<br>Defeat the Shishu Chochin and continue to the boss.
<br>Boss Tip!
Gorai the Uncaged will gain Worldly Pursuit, a rotating plus-shaped (+) AoE as well as Biwa Breaker which are successive hits of raidwide magic damage.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>Continue the path until the pile of crates.
<br>Climb the pile of crates to the second floor.
<br>Pull the Woven Rope.
<br>DO NOT kill the Shishu Chochin on the second floor.
<br>Aggro the Shishu Chochin and pull them down to the main floor.
<br>Kill them one at a time facing the lanterns.
<br>Take note!
The monster must be facing the lantern when it dies.<br>
It will cast a cone AoE upon death that must hit the lantern to light it up.<br>
This must be done for all three lanterns.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br><br>
<br>Ignore the Rokkon Sentinel.
<br>Clean all four Stones of Protection on the path leading up.
<br>Boss Tip!
Shishio will use Hanting Cry that will summon wildlife which will do a series of AoEs.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>Ignore the Rokkon Sentinel.
<br>Ignore the four Stones of Protection on the path.
<br>Boss Tip!
Shishio wil use Yoki which spawns AoEs that cover the arena with shifting sands which inflict Six Fulms Under. If this debuff expires, the player will die.<br>
Stand in the safe spot to remove the debuff then move into the sands to avoid getting hit by the massive AoE.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>Remove the Rokkon Sentinel.
<br>Use the emote Eastern Bow (/ebow) in front of the shrine.
<br>Topple Iwakura.
<br>Boss Tip!
Shishio will use Haunting Cry that will summon monsters with arrows, hide behind the correct one.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br>
<br>Remove Rokkon Sentinel.
<br>Use the emote Eastern Bow (/ebow) in front of the shrine.
<br>Topple Ancient Tree
<br>Boss Tip!
Shishio will use Haunting Cry that will summon ghosts which do damage on contact.
<br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br>Completing all 12 paths unlocks the Burabura Chochin Whistle.<br><img alt="burabura.jpg" src="images\burabura.jpg"><br><br><br><br><br><br>───── ⋆⋅☆⋅⋆ ─────<br>Date: 28/04/2024
Collected by: W'eylyn Mavourneen
Copy]]></description><link>mount-rokkon.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Mount Rokkon.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[W'eylyn Mavourneen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 07:45:55 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="images\mount_rokkon1.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images\mount_rokkon1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>